James Dumbell

Senior Software Engineer



+44 7421 138 662



London, UK



/james-dumbell



jdumbell92@gmail.com



/j-dumbell

About

Polyglot software engineer with expertise across web development, data engineering and devOps. Experience in leading engineering teams, embedding practices and agile ways of working. Functional programming advocate with an interest in systems programming.

Skills

Languages

Typescript, Scala, Golang, Python

Cloud & DevOps

AWS, GCP, Terraform, CDK, Serverless Framework, Docker, Github Actions

Databases

Postgres, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Snowflake

Frameworks

React, NestJS (REST), Apollo (GraphQL), Flask, Apache Spark, Pandas, Airflow, Dagster, DBT

Experience



Grafana Labs

Senior Software Engineer, Jun 2023 - Present

Senior software engineer at a global software company specializing in open source and SAS observability products.



Infinity Works

Senior Software Engineer, Jul 2021 - Jun 2023 Software Engineer, Jul 2019 - Jul 2021

Senior software engineer at a technology consultancy, working across a variety of London-based projects & clients:

Sainsbury's

- Built a serverless full-stack web app (Typescript, NodeJS, React, MongoDB) that allowed advertisers to build digital audiences and campaigns using Sainsbury's customer data.
- Developed the backend systems to process over 100 million daily supply chain datapoints and populate a datalake (S3) & data warehouse (Snowflake). Also built REST APIs (Python, Flask) to expose this data to other systems.

Convex

- Designed and implemented a number of core business web apps (NextJS) and backend services (NestJS, Golang, Postgres) for an insurtech scale-up to enable underwriters to capture data and manage workflows.
- Built services in Scala to orchestrate and ingest business data sources to an S3 datalake via Apache Spark jobs on EMR.



Wonderbly

Senior Growth Analyst, Sep 2018 - Jun 2019

Lead analyst and data engineer, working with data sources from across the business (including marketing, finance & operations).



Spark44

Data Engineer / Analyst, Oct 2016 - Sep 2018

Data engineer and analyst at the creative agency for Jaguar Land Rover.

Education



University of Manchester, 2011 - 2015 Master of Mathematics (MMath)



Wolverhampton Grammar School, 2004 - 2011 A-levels: Maths, Physics, Further maths, Chemistry

Certifications



Snowflake SnowPro Core, June 2020